Everyone is responsible
for reporting espionage .
Covering it up
is also a crime .
Severe punishment for those
who incite rebellious thoughts .
Subverting the government
will result in a death sentence .
Everyone is responsible
for reporting espionage .
Good morning , sir ...
Wear your cap properly .
Do it .
What 's inside your school bag ?
Open it .
Good morning , sir .
I told you not to bring it here .
Open your school bag .
Do it .
Don 't bring this to school
or you 'll get punished .
Come to my office during lunch break .
Thank you , sir .
You idiot . He could 've found the book .
- Good morning , sir ... - Wei Chungting .
Thank you .
Staring at that girl again ?
I heard Instructor Bai was searching Sheng 's schoolbag .
No big deal .
Don 't worry about it .
He needs to be more cautious .
We 'll be dead if we 're busted .
We 'd better be invisible to Instructor Bai 's eyes .
Salute the flag !
Magnificent landscape
Bountiful produce
We 're the best in East Asia
Never abandon hopes
Nor stand still
Glorify our nation
Make a better world
Come in .
Which author are we studying today ?
It 's Tagore .
Are you done with that ? It 's my turn .
Wait . We 're not done yet .
You 're copying the illustrations ? No wonder it 's taking you forever .
I just want to copy everything in it .
What if we don 't get to read it again ?
Well , hurry up .
Okay .
You should draw it properly . This looks ugly . Do it again .
Speak for yourself .
What 's that ? A rose apple ?
Mine is better than yours .
In the meantime , Dragon Warrior
descends from the sky to attack the devil by surprise .
- Hey . - What are you doing ?
- Give it back . - I 'm the mighty Dragon Warrior .
Instructor Bai scared me to death today .
Today we 're reading Tagore .
Not just because he was an important Indian poet .
He was also a philosopher who rebelled against British colonialism .
The leaf becomes a flower when it experiences love .
Weren 't we all born free ?
We deeply believed in this
while we hid in the school storeroom
copying those precious pages , word for word .
But ironically
we lived in an era in which
speaking about it was a crime
and reading banned books would cost us our lives .
During the Cold War in 1962 , Taiwan was under martial law .
All books promoting communism or left-wing thoughts
were strictly banned .
Anyone who reads them would be severely punished
and could receive a death sentence .
Tell me . Where are the books from ?
Are you in a conspiracy against the government ?
Confess , or die with your friends .
Hey .
We 'd get no testimony if he 's dead .
Hell . We 've pulled out all his fingernails and got nothing .
There 's no end to it .
What tormented me most
wasn 't being tortured by the Garrison Command
but those nightmares .
Every day , I told myself that if I die
I 'd stop having dreams about Greenwood High School
and any of them in the book club
or Fang Rayshin .
But when I finally lost consciousness
I realised that
that 's when the worst nightmare began .
Greenwood High School
Nightmare
Mr Chang .
Mr Chang !
The country
will be grateful to you .
It 's you .
Why are you still here at this late hour ?
I fell asleep .
Me too .
Everyone was gone when I woke up .
I 've a feeling
that I 've dreamt about this before .
I didn 't know we have a grave here
without a name on it .
Fang Rayshin
Let 's go .
Do you remember what happened before you fell asleep ?
I don 't remember anything .
The road is gone .
Hey .
Why don 't you have a seat ?
It 's so dusty here .
By the way
my name is Wei Chungting .
I 'm Fang Rayshin .
I know .
You 're a model student .
I 've seen your articles on the bulletin board .
That 's nothing compared to you .
You write about taboo stuff in your workbook .
Without fearing being caught by Instructor Bai .
Are you scared that I 'll tell on you ?
Hello ?
There 's only static .
Mr Chang ?
Get out of here .
Hello ?
I hear nothing .
Mr Chang is still here .
But this is the only phone in the school .
Are you sure it was him ?
Positive .
Even if he 'd called from somewhere else
how did he know we 're in the school ?
The windows are sealed .
I don 't think Mr Chang is inside .
" A certain subversive group has been found in the school . "
What does it mean ?
Where did he go ?
Mr Chang 's desk has been searched .
So was Miss Yin 's .
" Having a bad day ?
I feel better when I see you . "
" Did Instructor Bai give you a hard time ? "
Rayshin .
What did you see ?
Nothing .
What 's wrong ?
Rayshin .
Come with me .
In mourning
Why is this here ?
Doesn 't it mean someone 's dead ?
Where are we going ?
To ask the custodian for the key .
What key ?
The one to the storeroom .
Aren 't we here for Mr Chang ?
Something happened to our book club .
Mr Chang was one of us .
He 's in .
Uncle Gao .
Can I borrow the key ?
I fought all the battles with the Party for over 20 years
and killed countless enemies .
All my fellow soldiers knew that
no one loved the Party more than I did .
I merely got some cigarettes from you
and lent you the key .
And they charged me with what ?
Helping the insurgents ?
In conspiracy with the communists ?
To hell with them .
They beat me up
and pulled out all my teeth .
What has it got to do with me ?
Tell me .
You rascal !
What were you conspiring in that storeroom ?
You 're with the communists !
Run !
I 'll kill you to show my loyalty to the Party !
I 'll kill you all !
This way !
You got the wrong guy .
It 's not me .
You got it wrong
They 're with the communists .
Not me .
You got it wrong .
Everyone is responsible for reporting espionage .
Covering it up is also a crime .
Subverting the government
will result in a death sentence .
A death sentence .
Rayshin . We 're safe now .
What was that ?
Rayshin .
Let 's go .
Something did happen here .
You had a book club here with Mr Chang ?
Yes .
Every day after school
Miss Yin would bring a book
to read with us here .
But the one who started it
was Mr Chang Minghui .
Stop there !
I knew it was you .
You do it all the time .
You spell trouble . Take this away .
- I 'll do it after the ceremony . - Yeah , right .
Aren 't you a teacher ?
You should set a good example .
Mr Gao . Relax , have a cigarette .
Don 't be upset .
Here are the matches .
Listen . If this is still here after the ceremony
I 'll throw it away .
Got it , Mr Gao .
Mr Chang .
Good morning , Miss Yin .
Why are the military police here ?
- Not sure . - Are we having a drill ?
Are they here for us ?
Don 't make wild guesses .
Where 's Miss Yin ?
I haven 't seen Mr Chang either .
The military police are here .
Where 's Mr Huang ?
In the office .
Where are the books ?
Don 't worry , I 've hidden them .
If they 're here for me , just pretend you don 't know me .
Come what may , just protect the kids .
I know .
Magnificent landscape
Bountiful produce
We 're the best in East Asia
Never abandon hopes
Nor stand still
Let go !
Let me go !
The government is murdering people !
Carry on with the ceremony .
I said , carry on !
Magnificent landscape
Bountiful produce
We 're the best in East Asia
Never abandon hopes
Nor stand still
Glorify our nation
Make a better world
Louder !
Remember those who built the nation in hardship
Cherish what we have
Keep our feet on the ground
Let 's work together
Be persistent
Salute our national flag
Let 's work together
Be persistent
Salute our national flag
My dad said the Command can extort a confession by torture .
- Maybe Mr Huang will ... - I trust him .
Just like I trust you .
Then why do we have to stop ?
All the teachers are under investigation .
I can 't drag you in it .
But , Miss Yin ...
did they remove all the books ?
Mr Chang managed to save some
but it 's too dangerous to bring them here .
We can get them from him .
That 's right .
If the teachers are being watched , we 'll get the books .
No . I may not be able to help you if you 're caught .
Let 's start with me .
I 'll pretend to hand in my assignment .
Chang 's next . Then Mao
Wenxiong , Zhou Xin , and Sheng .
We 'll take turns to go .
But , even the teachers are being watched .
If one of us gets caught
are you sure he or she won 't betray us ?
I won 't .
And I know you won 't either .
- Be safe . - Goodbye , Miss Yin .
Goodbye , Miss Yin .
Return the key to Gao with this .
Got it .
Now go .
Sorry . Are you okay ?
I 'm fine .
Hey .
You won 't tell anyone , right ?
About what ?
I saw nothing but your music workbook .
Look at what happened to our school .
Our classes are the only ones marked with these .
The teachers ' desks were searched .
And we have these notices from the Command .
I think everyone got arrested .
But ...
he couldn 't have made the call if he was caught .
Maybe he 's hiding somewhere with the others .
We used to gather in a bomb shelter .
There 's an emergency phone in it .
Wait here . I 'll go and check it out .
Burn them with joss paper so no one will find out .
Wenxiong .
Did something happen to the book club ?
Are they hiding in the bomb shelter ?
Sheng told on us .
No way .
Then tell me .
Why was the book with Instructor Bai ?
Wasn 't it Sheng 's turn to pick it up this week ?
Keep it safe .
Didn 't you say that
no one would betray us ?
How did things end up like this ?
Mr Chang .
Why did you let Sheng join us in the first place ?
What do you mean ?
Wenxiong doesn 't like the fact
that he 's always playing with his puppets
instead of reading books .
Listen .
When I was a student just like Sheng
my mind was absent in class .
I was always drawing .
How I wished I had a teacher
who would give me some space
and allow me to draw
whenever I wanted to .
Maybe I could have become more than an art teacher .
But ...
Is it worth the risk
for our sake ?
Remember this ?
Among Tagore 's poems
there is one
which I like a lot .
" The leaf becomes a flower when it experiences love . "
" The flower bears fruit when it practises worship . "
" The roots beneath the earth claim no rewards
for making the branches fruitful . "
Wei Chungting .
How did things end up like this ?
All we did was read some books .
Wenxiong .
Wei ...
Chungting ...
Get out of here ...
Now !
Wenxiong !
Everyone is responsible for reporting espionage .
Covering it up is also a crime .
Severe punishment goes to those who incite rebellious thoughts .
Subverting the government
will result in a death sentence .
Run !
What was that thing ?
Is this place really our school ?
Miss Yin .
Wenxiong was killed .
- Miss Yin ... - Of course , he was .
Since the whistleblower is with you .
Why did you bring her here ?
Why is she here with you ?
She gave the book to Instructor Bai .
And got us all killed .
No .
It wasn 't me .
Rayshin .
Why did Miss Yin call you a whistleblower ?
I 've no idea .
Who gave you the book ?
Tell me .
It wasn 't me . I know nothing .
Why did you do it ?
Answer me !
In mourning
It wasn 't me .
I didn 't do it .
Hello ?
What 's this for ?
Doesn 't it mean someone 's dead ?
You 're the whistleblower ...
It 's you .
Why are you still here so late at night ?
I think I 've dreamt about this before .
I hear nothing .
Mr Chang is still here .
By the way , I 'm Wei Chungting .
I 'm Fang Rayshin .
The Whistleblower
What the hell do you mean ?
You do whatever you want with those women .
But I don 't want anything to do with them .
What women ?
Leave me alone .
Tell me again . What women are you talking about ?
Are you trying to ruin my day ?
Don 't touch me .
What women ?
Please leave me alone .
You should be the one leaving me alone .
Help me , Goddess of Mercy ...
I have to listen to those murmuring old men at work .
And your muttering at home too ?
What have I done to deserve this ?
You heard everything from your room ?
Don 't be like your mum .
Constantly paranoid .
My marriage is ill-fated .
Please answer my prayer .
And give me a sign .
I 'm going to school .
Please answer my prayer . Please show me a sign .
Last night , an underground publisher was busted
after investigation by the Command .
They distributed banned books
under the cover of being a bookstore .
The owners are under arrest .
The Command wants you to report all those who look suspicious .
Do not cover up for the criminals .
Open the schoolbag .
Do it .
Why did you bring this to school ?
You 'll get punished , do you know that ?
Attention , everyone .
All students from Class 302 , that 's led by Mr Huang
please report to Instructor Bai after school .
You will be offered counselling on patriotism .
Fang Rayshin .
Sir .
Brief history of our school
Miss Li from the School Annals Room told me about this .
If this gets investigated , the consequences will be dire .
Do you know that ?
Yes , sir .
Your father is going to be promoted .
Don 't get yourself into trouble .
Instructor Bai .
Mr Chang .
She 's a student under my supervision .
Is she in trouble ?
She 's fine .
Instructor Bai .
I 've made a college admission questionnaire
for the senior students .
Can I ask for her help ?
Please excuse us then .
Mr Chang .
After what happened to Mr Huang
we 're going to investigate the staff .
You 'll have to pardon us
if we offend you in any way .
Fang Rayshin .
I 'm here to help if you need me .
Let 's go .
You had fun doodling on the principals ' faces ?
I 'm sorry , Mr Chang .
Fill in the questionnaire and go back to class .
Having a bad day ?
I feel better when I see you .
Did Instructor Bai give you a hard time ?
You 're lucky Instructor Bai has been nice to you .
Don 't take that for granted .
Understood .
Why did Mr Huang bring banned books to school ?
Now he 's gone and we 're under investigation .
Quiet .
I heard they even questioned his wife .
God knows how many more people will be implicated .
Are you all right ?
Are you coming tonight ?
I have to go .
Go back to class now .
I thought you weren 't coming .
A student of mine came to hand over the assignment .
Drawing daffodils again ?
Yeah .
What 's so special about them ?
There are much prettier flowers .
Daffodils look uncomplicated .
And they live in their own world
without paying any mind to what people think .
That 's why I like them .
They must feel so lonely .
Not at all .
As long as someone understands them .
I 'll teach you to play a song .
Military Police
Help me , Goddess of Mercy ...
It 's about time , sir .
Don 't make it difficult for us .
My apologies .
Where are you going , Dad ?
Ask your mum to call Instructor Bai .
They don 't know what they 're doing .
Dad .
Dad !
Where are they taking you ?
Get your mum to call Instructor Bai .
Got that ? Call Instructor Bai .
Drive .
Dad .
Dad !
Mum , Dad wanted you to call Instructor Bai ...
Mum .
- Dad wanted you to call ... - He 'll be fine .
They said that it was just a small corruption charge .
He 'll be fine .
The Goddess has answered my prayer .
I found your dad 's account book
soon after I prayed to the Goddess .
It was you .
Do you know what I prayed for ?
You told on him .
I asked the Goddess of Mercy ...
to make him gone for good .
When the rain stops , I 'll walk you home .
You can 't stay here for the night .
But I have nowhere to go .
Your dad is Bai 's good friend .
I 'm sure he 'll be home soon .
Why don 't you stay home tomorrow ?
We can watch a movie another day .
No , I 'm going .
It 's the only thing I 'm looking forward to now .
Turn around .
As long as we 're alive
there are lots of things to look forward to .
Done .
Have some rest .
I 'll walk you home later .
Will you be by my side ?
You won 't leave me like they did , right ?
Why did you do it ?
Why ?
Mr Chang .
( Anti-communist and Anti-Russian aggression song )
I think this song is about to be banned soon .
Then I 'll play it as often as I can .
Why are you suddenly interested in playing the piano ?
I heard this song from a friend .
So I want to learn it .
We need to talk about something .
What 's going on
between you and Fang Rayshin ?
Stop before it 's too late .
I asked you to help her manage her troubles at home .
Not to draw her into your arms .
There 's nothing between us .
What if someone sees you with her ?
Have you thought about the consequences ?
We 're in a crisis here .
She 'd be implicated if you 're caught .
I 'll sort it out with her .
But what about us ?
You 're not just responsible for yourself .
You must make a choice .
Leave her ...
or get out of our book club .
Why haven 't you come to meet me lately ?
I read your questionnaire .
Everything looks fine .
You seem emotionally stable now .
So we can stop with my counselling .
You lied to me .
You promised to stay with me .
That 's a gift for you .
Just give it to Miss Yin .
Fang Rayshin .
Didn 't I tell you to come to me if you need help ?
Let go !
Do you know what I prayed for ?
If only she 's gone for good .
Right ?
In mourning
Death to the whistleblower
Sheng .
What are you doing here ?
Wei Chungting .
I couldn 't find it .
I couldn 't find the head of my puppet .
Here it is . Look .
I 'm the Dragon Warrior .
Mr Dragon Warrior .
You 've been participating in subversive activities ...
to try and overturn our government .
I hereby sentence you to death .
Do you understand ?
Answer me .
Sheng .
Did you give the book to Rayshin ?
Are you going to beat me up too ?
I won 't hurt you ...
but you have to tell me the truth .
I swore ...
not to tell anybody .
Who made you swear to secrecy ?
I swore I won 't tell
even if you kill me ...
Who made you swear to secrecy ?
Wenxiong called me a snitch .
Chang and Mao beat me up
and locked me in the toolshed .
But I didn 't tell anyone .
Wei Chungting .
I didn 't tell anyone ...
that you had the book .
Wei Chungting .
You didn 't give it to anyone , did you ?
You didn 't betray us , right ?
Don 't you want to know why you 're here ?
This is where the sinful dead belong .
Soon , you 'll join the rest
to stay here forever .
Tell me .
Are you in a conspiracy against the government ?
If you want to be with Mr Chang ...
just give me the book .
Teacher-in-charge : Yin Tsuihan
Hey .
You won 't tell anyone , right ?
Keep it safe .
Can I borrow the book that you were reading ?
No .
It 's not mine .
Can you borrow it for me ?
Forget it .
I 'll get it myself .
Rayshin .
Sheng .
I 'm going to Mr Chang during the break .
So , I 'll get the book for you .
Really ?
Yeah .
But don 't tell them that we switched .
We 'll get in trouble
if they find out .
Don 't worry .
I swear I won 't tell anyone .
Okay .
Wei Chungting .
Thank you .
Rayshin .
Can I study with you in the future ?
Sure .
Fathers and Sons by Ivan Turgenev
Fang Rayshin .
I 'll try my best to save your father .
Will Miss Yin ...
get fired ?
Don 't worry .
The country will be grateful to you .
If only you were gone for good .
I 've finally found you .
Don 't ever leave me again .
But you 're the only one left here .
Chang Minghui
You set up an underground group
that provided the students with subversive books
and incited them to rebel against the government .
You 're hereby sentenced to death .
Do you understand me ?
Answer me !
Mr Chang .
Execute him .
No !
Murderer .
- The actual snitch . - The real whistleblower .
Your selfishness has cost us our lives .
- Murderer . - I just wanted to break them up !
Murderer ...
Run ... get out of here .
You can 't get away . Wherever you go , you 're stuck here .
Murderer ...
I didn 't mean it . It wasn 't me .
It 's not my fault
I 'm sorry . I didn 't do it .
Ignore them . Just ignore them .
I didn 't mean it .
Let me go .
You 'll just go through it over and over .
Again and again .
It 's not my fault .
Have you forgotten about it
or are you just afraid ?
or are you too afraid to remember ?
I remember it now .
I 've confessed my crime in front of everyone .
I 'm sorry .
For what ?
I caused everyone 's death ...
including yours .
You made a mistake
but it was not you who killed us .
You were just being used .
Is it too late for amends ?
As long there 's someone still alive
there 's always hope .
But I don 't have another chance .
The dead are gone forever .
You can 't bring them back to life .
It 's a shame
we didn 't get to live to see freedom .
But those who are alive will .
The only thing you can do now
is to help him get out of here .
Someone has to live to remember
how difficult it has been to get freedom .
Wei Chungting .
Throw him in .
No one has made it except for him .
Give him a couple of days .
Shoot him if he doesn 't confess .
Yes , sir .
If only I hadn 't met you .
An underground book club has been busted
with a total of six students
and two teachers arrested .
The insurgents include these students ...
You Shengjie
Zhou Xin
Chang Xuchang
Huang Wenxiong
and Li Zhihao .
The leaders of the club are these teachers ...
Yin Tsuihan
and Chang Minghui .
They 're both sentenced to death .
The subversive student Wei Chungting
has been put under arrest today .
Fang Rayshin .
What are you doing ?
Are you sheltering the insurgent ?
Rayshin !
Whatever 's happened is history .
Just let bygones be bygones .
Stop listening .
Don 't try to recall anything .
Leave all the pain in the past .
It 's easier to forget , isn 't it ?
No .
I don 't want to forget .
I won 't forget anymore .
Wei Chungting .
No !
No .
Just leave the past behind you .
I 'm getting him out of here .
Come over to me .
Go .
I 'll stay here .
Are you kidding me ?
I have to face my sins .
I 'm in it too , I 'll stay with you .
You need to live to remember this .
There is hope if one of us is alive .
That 's what Mr Chang told me .
Honesty . Righteousness . Diligence . Humility .
Fang Rayshin !
Wei Chungting .
Thank you .
Fang Rayshin !
We 've been given an order .
Execute him if he still won 't speak .
I think he 's dead . It 's been days .
I 'm ...
I 'm making a confession .
Charge me with whatever you want .
But I want to live .
The ones who survived
Mr Chang .
It 's been years
and I couldn 't find the courage to do what you asked .
Chang Minghui 's grave
They 're demolishing the school .
If I don 't go back now
I won 't be able to face you again .
New Apartments for Sale Best Deals Ever !
Greenwood High School
Honesty . Righteousness . Diligence . Humility .
" We have both animalistic "
" and demonic nature "
" but at the same time we also possess divinity . "
" We have the desire "
" for both individualism and altruism . "
Wei Chungting .
Do you know the book that I 'm quoting from ?
The Symbol of Anguish
You know where it is .
Find it .
There 's a letter in it .
Give it to someone for me .
I will .
Chang Minghui .
Wei Chungting .
You must live on .
Promise me . You have to stay alive .
Live and you 'll be free someday .
Mr Chang .
I have to go .
Don 't go .
Mr Chang !
The Symbol of Anguish
Mr Chang left this for you .
To my daffodil , I 'll wait for you in our next life .
Here 's to liberty .
I will remember all of this .
I won 't ever forget it .
Here 's to liberty .
Translator : SPECTRA MEDIA